Inventory of the Louis Paul Lochner collection, 1933-1946
Hoover Institution Archives
Louis Paul Lochner collection
1925-1966
XX031
Hoover Institution Archives
10 manuscript boxes (3.8 linear feet)
Correspondence, writings, reports, and printed matter relating to the Nazi party, domestic conditions in Germany and German foreign policy before and during World War II, post-war occupation of Germany, denazification efforts, and communist party activities in Germany. Includes correspondence of Joachim von Ribbentrop.
Lochner, Louis Paul, 1887-
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
American political activist, journalist, and author.
Scope and Contents of Collection
Correspondence, writings, reports, and printed matter relating to the Nazi party, domestic conditions in Germany and German foreign policy before and during World War II, post-war occupation of Germany, denazification efforts, and communist party activities in Germany. Includes correspondence of Joachim von Ribbentrop.
The individual folder titles are Lochner's.
Separated Materials Note
Some items have been transferred to the Hoover Institution Library or incorporated into the following collections:
Franz von Papen miscellaneous papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Benno Reifenberg typescript, Hoover Institution Archives
Hellmuth Wissmann writings, Hoover Institution Archives
Kommunistishce Partei Deutschlands.; Nationalsozialistische deutsche Arbeiter-Partei.; Communism--Germany.; Communism.; Denazification.; Germany--Foreign relations--1933-1945.; Germany--History--1933-1945.; Germany--History--1945-1955.; Germany.; National socialism.; World War, 1939-1945--Germany.; World War, 1939-1945.
- Register, undated (Box-folder 1: 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Written by Lochner, contains his own descriptions of the materials found in the collection along with his opinion of their significance.
- Ribbentrop Office File, 1933-1936, 1966 (Boxes 1-2)
  Correspondence with Hitler and Hitler's Adjutants, etc. (originals and carbons) regarding German-British relations. Includes newspaper clippings.
  - General, circa 1966 (Box-folder 1: 2)
    Handwritten note explaining the provenance of these papers, as well as copies of original folders with notes by Herbert Hoover and Agnes Peterson.
  - Correspondence, 1935-1936
    Also included in the correspondent files are letters from Ribbentrop's office staff (Abetz, Bottiger, Falke, von Raumer, Rodde, and Thorner).
    - Unidentified, 1935 December 10 (Box-folder 1: 3)
      Letter to Ribbentrop re problems of authority in German-British relations. Carbon copy.
    - Hassel, Ulrich von, 1935 March 29 (Box-folder 1: 4)
      Report from Rome on a meeting with Suvich. Telegram.
    - Hess, Rudolf, 1934 September 13 (Box-folder 1: 5)
      Re Daniel Vincent. Telegram.
    - Hitler, Adolf, 1935-1936
      Contains Ribbentrop correspondence only.
      - undated (Box-folder 1: 6)
        Holograph in pencil re Sir Ruthermere's visit to Germany.
      - 1935 January 6 (Box-folder 1: 7)
        Holograph in black ink with attached translation of letter by A. L. Kennedy to Ribbentrop re his article in the Times.
      - 1935 January 16 (Box-folder 1: 8)
        Telegram re Genfsitzung.
      - 1935 January 20 (Box-folder 1: 9)
        Signed typescript re Lord Allen of Hurthwood's visit to Germany.
      - 1935 April 3 (Box-folder 1: 10)
        Holograph with attached "Entwurf eines Briefes des Reichsaussenministers an den Staatssekretar des Ausseren Sir John Simon, London, Foreign Office."
      - 1935 July 19 (Box-folder 1: 11)
        Signed typescript re visit of British soldiers.
      - 1936 August 11 (Box-folder 1: 12)
        Signed typescript re Ribbentrop's nomination as German ambassador to London. Includes two notes for the press and note by [Constantin] Freiherr von Neurath.
    - Hoare, Samuel, 1935 June 18 (Box-folder 1: 13)
      Typescript re limitation of naval forces.
    - Schaub, Julius, 1936 October 29 (Box-folder 1: 14)
    - Wiedemann, Fritz, 1935 January 30-1936 September 28 (Box-folder 1 :15)
    - Miscellaneous, 1936 (Box-folder 1: 16)
  - Reports, 1933-1936, undated
    Includes reports, translations of letters and articles from the foreign press, notes for Hitler (Notizen für den Kanzler), telephone conversation transcripts, etc., arranged in chronological order, signed or with written notes by Ribbentrop. Typescripts unless otherwise noted. The documents often explicitly mention Hitler as the addressee. If the documents carry a title, these are given in German.
    - General, 1933-1936 (Box-folder 1: 17)
      Not signed by Joachim von Ribbentrop. Includes DNB (Deutsches Nachrichtenburo) press reports, as well as undated documents.
    - "Aktennotizen" re German British relations, undated (Box-folder 1: 18)
    - "Besprechung mit dem baskischen Abgeordneten Ybornegeray und Herrn Pirroneau, massgebender Mann beim Echo de Paris bei Brinon in dessen Wohnung,", undated (Box-folder 1: 19)
    - "Fruhstuck bei General Bourret,", undated (Box-folder 1: 20)
    - "Material für den Kanzler" re French and English press, undated (Box-folder 1: 21)
    - "Notiz für den Kanzler, Frankreich,", undated (Box-folder 1: 22)
      Holograph.
    - "Notiz für den Kanzler, England,", undated (Box-folder 1: 23)
    - "Times Artikel von morgen,", undated (Box-folder 1: 24)
    - "Unterredung eines Freundes von mir mit dem englischen Konig,", undated (Box-folder 2: 1)
    - "Aktennotiz,", 1933 November 20-26 (Box-folder 2: 2)
      Re meetings with British statesmen that lead to more friendly German-British relations.
    - "Besprechung zwischen Monsieur Dupuy, Herrn de Brinon und mir,", 1933 December 1 (Box-folder 2: 3)
    - "Notizen für den Kanzler" re Great Britain and France, 1934 January 9 (Box-folder 2: 4)
    - "Notizen für den Kanzler" re meeting with von Neurath, 1934 February 2 (Box-folder 2: 5)
    - "Ubersetzung eines Briefes von Mr. Tennant...,", 1934 February 7 (Box-folder 2: 6)
    - "Notizen für den Kanzler,", 1934 February 9 (Box-folder 2: 7)
    - "Betrifft Besuch Eden,", 1934 February 19 (Box-folder 2: 8)
    - "Betrifft Besprechung Eden,", 1934 February 21 (Box-folder 2: 9)
    - Re Hitler's meeting with Eden and re Ribbentrop's role as Hitler's confidant in questions of foreign policy, 1934 February 21 (Box-folder 2: 10)
    - "Notiz für den Kanzler" re trip to Paris and "Allgemeine Eindrucke in Frankreich,", 1934 February 28 (Box-folder 2: 11)
    - "Besprechung mit Herrn Louis Barthou, franzosischem Aussenminister,", 1934 March 4 (Box-folder 2: 12)
      Signed holograph note attached.
    - "Notiz für den Kanzler" re France and Austria, 1934 March 15 (Box-folder 2: 13)
    - Re meeting with Sir Eric Phipps, 1934 April 28 (Box-folder 2: 14)
    - "Notiz für den Kanzler über englische Reise,", 1934 August 25 (Box-folder 2: 15)
    - "Besprechungen der franzosischen Frontkampferfuhrer mit Vertretern ihrer Regierung im Anschluss Berliner Reise 2-3 November 1934,", 1934 November 8 (Box-folder 2: 16)
    - "Unterhaltung mit dem franzosischen Aussenminister Laval,", 1934 December 6 (Box-folder 2: 17)
    - "Notiz für den Kanzler. Betrifft: Rothermere-Atrikel,", 1934 December 6 (Box-folder 2: 18)
    - "Bericht uber drei Wochen in England,", 1934 December 18 (Box-folder 2: 19)
    - "Ubersetzung,", 1934 December 22 (Box-folder 2: 20)
      Translation of a letter by George Chichester to von Ribbentrop.
    - "Zusamnenfassender Bericht uber die deutschfanzosische Frontkampferaktion von Winter 1933/1934 bis Jahresende 1934,", 1934 December 31 (Box-folder 2: 21)
      Written by Abetz, signed by Ribbentrop.
    - "Auszug aus einem Interview, das Jean Goy der Wochenschrift Notre Temps am 5.1.1935 gab,", 1935 January 5 (Box-folder 2: 22)
    - "Ubersetzung aus der Times vom 5.1.1935" re Eden, 1935 January 5 (Box-folder 2: 23)
    - "Einige in den letzten Tagen vom Ausland erhaltene Nachrichten," and "Notiz für den Führer und Reichskanzler,", 1935 January 14 (Box-folder 2: 24)
      Re an important article by A.L. Kennedy (Times).
    - "Notiz für den Führer und Reichskanzler,", 1935 January 14 (Box-folder 2: 25)
      Includes six articles from the foreign press.
    - "Betrifft Londoner Reise zwecks Forderung deutsch-englischer Wirtschafts-beziehungen. Entsendung einer offiziellen Goodwill Commission nach Deutschland...,", 1935 February 14 (Box-folder 2: 26)
    - "Brief von Lord Lothian," and "Vertrauliche Ausserungen von Lord Lothian uber Gegensatze in Berlin,", 1935 February 20-26 (Box-folder 2: 27)
    - "Abetz: Bericht Reise Paris-Brussel 16-25 Februar 1935,", 1935 February 25 (Box-folder 2: 28)
    - "Notiz für den Führer" re tactical areas, 1935 February 27 (Box-folder 2: 29)
    - "Notiz für den Kanzler. Italienische Verstandigungspropaganda in Frankreich,", 1935 February 27 (Box-folder 2: 30)
    - "Notiz für den Führer,", 1935 April 3 (Box-folder 2: 31)
      Re foreign relations with France and England.
    - "Notiz für den Führer. Betrifft Osterreichfrage,", 1935 July 4 (Box-folder 2: 32)
    - "Notiz für den Führer. Betrifft englischen Frontkampferbesuch,", 1935 July 4 (Box-folder 2: 33)
    - "Betrifft Herrn von Stohrer, Herrn von Keller, Pg. Reinebeck,", 1935 July 19 (Box-folder 2: 34)
    - "Notiz für den Führer" re England, 1935 October 29 (Box-folder 2: 35)
    - "Notiz für den Führer Betr. Reichsbankprasident Schacht,", 1935 November 12 (Box-folder 2: 36)
    - "Notiz für den Führer" re Rustungsproblem, 1935 December 8 (Box-folder 2: 37)
    - Translation of letter by Londonderry to von Ribbentrop, 1936 February 21 (Box-folder 2: 38)
    - Re Ribbentrop's and Dieckhoff's handing over a German document to Eden, 1936 April 1 (Box-folder 2: 39)
      Sent as telegram from London to Berlin. The document was titled "grosser konstruktiver Friedensplan" and was handed over in the presence of Lord Halifax and Mr. Wigram.
    - Re instructions to Furst Bismarck in London, 1936 July 22 (Box-folder 2: 40)
    - Re visit of Sir Oswald Mosley, 1936 September 11 (Box-folder 2: 41)
    - Re visit of Graf Bonmartini, owner of Giornale d'Italia, 1936 September 13 (Box-folder 2: 42)
    - Translation of letter by Londonderry to von Ribbentrop, 1936 September 16 (Box-folder 2: 43)
    - "Betrifft Besuch Sir Oswald Mosley beim Führer,", 1936 September 17 (Box-folder 2: 44)
    - Re Degrelle's visit, 1936 September 25 (Box-folder 2: 45)
    - "Betrifft Reichskolonialbund,", 1936 Semptember 25 (Box-folder 2: 46)
    - Re Italy, 1936 October 11 (Box-folder 2: 47)
      Includes a copy of Ribbentrop's letter to German ambassador to Italy von Hassel.
    - "Betrifft den lettischen Aussenminister Munters,", 1936 October 12 (Box-folder 2: 48)
    - "Notiz für den Führer Beiliegend einte korrespondenz mit Lord Londonderry,", 1936 October 12 (Box-folder 2: 49)
    - "Betrifft Japan-Verhandlungen,", 1936 October 13 (Box-folder 2: 50)
  - Subject file, 1935-1936
    - Austria, 1936 July 25 (Box-folder 2: 51)
      Letter from Hitler to Franz von Papen nominating him ambassador to Austria.
    - Ribbentrop, Joachim von, circa 1935-1936 (Box-folder 2: 52)
      Contains a report on a car accident in which Ribbentrop was involved; three letters of congratulation on Ribbentrop's birthday from Hitler, Bruckner, and Schaub; and a letter from Richard Ribbentrop thanking Hitler for a Christmas gift.
    - Miscellaneous, 1936 July 24 (Box-folder 2: 53)
      Letter from Staatssekretar Otto Meissner to Julius Schaub.
- German-Russian relations, 1939-1940
  Lochner's translations of documents and telegrams.
  - Summary, 1946 September 19 (Box-folder 2: 54)
    Based on documents found in the German Foreign Office. Contains information on German-Russian relations from 1922 to June 24, 1941.
  - Telegrams, 1939 (Box-folder 2: 55)
  - Telegrams, 1940 (Box-folder 2: 56)
  - Telegrams, 1941 (Box-folder 2: 57)
  - "Accord on Spoils Cited by Germans," Times, 1946 (Box-folder 2: 58)
  - "Molotov-Ribbentrop Secret Protocol," The Tablet (London), 1946 October 19 (Box-folder 2: 59)
- Nine letters from Count Potocki to Polish Minister of Foreign Affairs, 1937-1939 (Box-folder 2: 60)
- Bernard, General, 1945 May 28 (Box-folder 3: 1)
  Contains a report of a meeting with Hitler.
- Brauchitsch, 1941 (Box-folder 3: 2)
  Contains a letter from a member of resistance to Brauchitsch.
- Church - in Germany prior to WWII, circa 1933-1937 (Box-folder 3: 3)
- Church - in Germany after WWII, circa 1945 (Box-folder 3: 4)
- Communism, 1946 May 1 (Box-folder 3: 5)
- Correspondence - miscellaneous, circa 1925-1946 (Box-folder 3: 6)
- Documents, 1940 August (Box-folder 3: 7)
  Contains copies of documents drawn up by Keitel and Ribbentrop.
- Essays, circa 1945-1947 (Box-folder 3: 8)
  Re conditions in Germany during and after WWII.
- French Occupation Zone, essay, undated (Box-folder 3: 9)
- German Law, 1935 August 24 (Box-folder 3: 10)
  Contains a history and interpretation of certain paragraphs of the law.
- Gestapo - Arrest of Pastor Moerike, 1938 April 10 (Box-folder 3: 11)
- Goerdeler, Karl, circa 1945 February (Box-folder 3: 12)
  Contains a copy of a letter to Mrs. Goerdeler in commemoration of her husband's death.
- Hitler and Christianity, circa 1941 (Box-folder 3: 13)
- Jews - persecution of during WWII, circa 1941 (Box-folder 3: 14)
- Kleffel, Walter, circa 1946 (Box-folder 3: 15)
  A well-known publicist. Contains his thoughts about Germany.
- Lammers, Clemens (Dr.), 1948 July 14 (Box-folder 3: 16)
  Leading German industrialist. Contains excerpts from a letter to Lochner.
- Lochner, Louis, circa 1945-1946 (Box-folder 3: 17)
  Includes requests, thank yous, and other personal documents.
- Miscellaneous, circa 1931-1949 (Box-folder 3: 18)
- Miscellaneous requests to Occupation Forces in Germany, circa 1945 (Box-folder 3: 19)
- Nazi concentration camps, circa 1945 April (Box-folder 3: 20)
- Polish and Russian occupation, circa 1945-1946 (Box-folder 3: 21)
  Contains reports from East German provinces.
- Politics - Germany after WWII, circa 1945 (Box-folder 3: 22)
- Press, 1945 July 25 (Box-folder 3: 23)
  Contains a typescript re the reconstruction of press in post-Hitler Germany.
- Refugees (German), circa 1945-1946 (Box-folder 3: 24)
  Includes information about their hardship and appeals for help.
- Relief work of churches in Germany after WWII, circa 1947 (Box-folder 3: 25)
- Reports from West Germany after WWII, circa 1947-1948 (Box-folder 3: 26)
- Rommel, Erwin Generalfeldmarschall, 1945 March 7 (Box-folder 3: 27)
  Contains a copy of a letter to Mrs. Rommel regarding the erection of a monument honoring Rommel.
- Russian occupation, circa 1945 (Box-folder 3: 28)
  Contains documents re the events in Koenigsberg since April 9, 1945, including a partial list of persons arrested.
- Schroder, G. (Pastor), 1946 March 30 (Box-folder 3: 29)
  Contains a bound typewritten manuscript, "Aber von innen gesehen...," which details Schroder's experiences and some events during the Third Reich.
- SS (Schutzstaffel) - history, circa 1938-1939 (Box-folder 3: 30)
- Some opinions, circa 1948-1951 (Box-folder 3: 31)
  Contains typescripts, an article, and a report written right after the German collapse and in the years following. Includes a typescript by Dr. Piening.
- "Sowjet Union" - German report, 1945 (Box-folder 3: 32)
- Sudeten Germans, 1938 (Box-folder 3: 33)
- Thomas, General (German), 1945 July 20 (Box-folder 4: 1)
  Contains a typescript discussing his position regarding Hitler prior to WWII and his arrest in connection with the July 20, 1944 Hitler assassination attempt.
- U.S. and British Occupation Forces, circa 1945-1948 (Box-folder 4: 2)
- Vorspiel Zum Krieg Im Osten, 1944 (Box-folder 4: 3)
  Contains a review of book by Grigore Gragencu.
- Wulle, R., 1938-1942 (Box-folder 4: 4)
  Contains an appeal describing Wulle's experiences under the Nazi Party.
- Zienau, Oswald, 1946 June 13 (Box-folder 4: 5)
  Contains a letter to Lochner with a list of 126 persons executed by the Nazis.
- Anti and pro-Nazi underground materials, 1939, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 4: 6-7)
  Contains leaflets, newsletters, news clippings, and other printed matter. Includes a copy of the publication Hitler: Doomed to Die.
- Miscellaneous printed matter, circa 1929-1956 (Box-folder 4: 8-14)
  Contains articles, magazines, pamphlet, newspaper clippings, and other printed matter mainly regarding Nazi Germany. Includes a copy of the speech "Erfahrungen in Russland und Folgerung für die sozial-politsche Aufgabe der Christen im Westen" by H. Gollwitzer given on March 26, 1953, a memo titled "Denkschrift über die gegenwärtigen Probleme der Entnazifizierung," and the book Wir Kriegsblinden und Unsere Gemeinschaft 1916-1956.
- Excerpts from Weekly Political Intelligence and German Opinion Review, 1945-1946, undated (Box-folder 5: 1)
- Resolution by all political parties represented in the Provisional Parliament of Great Hesse, 1946 June 7 (Box-folder 5: 2)
  Objects to the manner in which houses were being requisitioned for occupation troops.
- Documents re the sufferings and migrations of German Expelles from Silesia and the Sudetenland, undated (Box-folder 5: 3)
  The papers were contributed by the Office of the Catholic Monsigneur Albert Buttner, who conducted a Kirchliche Hilfsstelle in Frankfurt, Germany and include eye-witness accounts of the migrations, mainly in German. Includes the typescript "The Czech Conquest of Saaz, Sudetengau."
- A Check List of Current Serials in the United States Zone of Germany, 1946 September (Box-folder 5: 4)
  Prepared by the Library of Congress Mission HQ, U S. Forces, European Theater, APO 757, U.S. Army.
- One page memorandum, undated (Box-folder 5: 5)
  Discusses how the Soviets tried to make the other parties in the town of Parchim, Mechlemberg in Germany come into the communist fold. Contributed by Gerd Niehoff.
- Bierzeitung, 1935 September (Box-folder 5: 6)
  A humorous mimeographed monthly paper published by the staff personnel of the 2nd German Infantry Regiment stationed at Munster.
- Case history of a complaint and its disposition by Dr. Clemens Kauffmann, 1946 (Box-folder 5: 7)
  Kauffmann was an appointed health officer of the Berlin section of Lichterfelde. The complaint regards Kauffmann's ejection from his home after being assured that it would not be requisitioned upon assuming his post as a health officer.
- Three papers on German finance, 1946, undated (Box-folder 5: 8)
  Submitted by Dr. Noll Von Nahmer, a ministerial director in the Reich Ministry of Finance.
- Project for a periodic correspondence letter, undated (Box-folder 5: 9)
  Submitted by Dr. Theordore Beuchner, a German journalist. Includes material in German with Buechner's English translations.
- "Imperialist Methods of Government,", 1946 (Box-folder 5: 10)
  Copy of an article supplied to the students of the English Seminary of Berlin University, which was then located in the Russian sector of the city. The article contains criticisms of the Britain and the United States.
- Case history of Dr. Rudolf Pander, 1946 (Box-folder 5: 11)
  Contains a request by Palmer in English for better treatment as a prisoner of war. Also includes a letter to Lochner in German.
- "Die Bruecke" (The Bridge), 1946 (Box-folder 5: 12)
  A typescript copy of an article written by a German prisoner of war in Egypt. This soldier tries to make clear to the youth of Germany how wrong the ideologies which they followed were. He discusses constructing "The Bridge" toward establishing a New Germany which shall lead Germany back into the family of nations.
- "Der Brand von Wurzburg" (The Wurtzburg Fire), 1946 March 16 (Box-folder 5: 13)
  Contains an eye-witness account of the disaster by Prof. Dr. Hermann Luedke, a native of Wurzburg until 1946, when he was appointed chief of all the city hospitals in Schweinfurt and health officer for the district.
- Abraham Lincoln, play by Dr. Hermann Leudke, 1938 (Box-folder 5: 14)
  Includes a copy of a letter by Leudke.
- "Germany" letter, undated (Box-folder 5: 15)
  Copy of a letter in German written by Ruth Fischer. The letter was screened by Germany's Civil Censorship Division at Offenbach and was deemed important enough that a copy of it was made for intelligence purposes. In it the writer outlines a Soviet Russian plot for turning Germany into a Bolshevik State.
- Exposé on the future of the German press, undated (Box-folder 5: 16)
  Written at the request of the German government by Dr. Hermann Katzengerger, former press-officer in the German Foreign Office.
- Clay and the Catholic Bishops, 1946 July 3 (Box-folder 5: 17)
  Contains a letter written by General Clay stating that he is unwilling to pass along a petition to President Truman, written by a group of Catholic bishops assembled in Fulda, Germany, asking that assistance be given to expellees from Eastern Germany to ease their suffering.
- Story of the surrender of the city of Heidenheim by Hans Voith, undated (Box-folder 5: 18)
  Typescript in German describing how the citizens of the Suabian city of Heidenheim outwitted the Nazis who had intended to bomb the city. Given to Lochner by a Stuttgart military intelligence officer.
- Sidelights on Soviet occupation, 1946 (Box-folder 5: 19)
  Contains documents from intelligence officers in Berlin which discuss the daily disagreements between American and Russian authorities in Berlin.
- Speech ascribed to Cardinal von Galen, circa 1946 (Box-folder 5: 20)
  Copy of a speech in German that circulated widely among Catholics with the claim that it was delivered in Rome by Cardinal von Galen in March 1946. It aims to provoke suspicion in the occupation authorities.
- Protocols of the first two sessions of the provisional people's parliament for Wurtemberg-Baden, 1946 January 16 (Box-folder 5: 21)
  Contains two copies of "Verhandlungen der Vorläufigen Volksvertretung für Württemberg-Baden."
- Sidelights on the German Communist Party, 1946 August 12 (Box-folder 5: 22)
  Contains a typescript in German regarding the Communist Party's demand for land reform as well as their objection to the writing of constitutions for the three sections of Germany and to occupation by American troops on the grounds that it would prevent German unity. Also includes a summary of Soviet tactics in Berlin and their dealings with the Democratic parties.
- Stuttgart politics, 1946, undated (Box-folder 5: 23)
  Contains a report by Lord Mayor Klett on one year of occupation and reconstruction; a special edition of Rhine Neckar Zeitung showing the results of the election of delegates to the provisional parliament of Wurtemburg-Baden; an edition of Stuttgart Zeitung; three copies of an open letter to Dr. Schumacher, leader of the Social-Democrats; and a copy of the speech Für Frieden, Freiheit, und Sozialismus (Peace, Freedom, and Socialism) by Dr. Kurt Schumacher.
- Nazi card of condolence, undated (Box-folder 5: 24)
  A copy of a stock card sent to the families of fallen German soldiers.